Hi, Guys!
Today, we are here
at Bolagos National High School.
Of course,
I am with my very demure,
very mindful,
and very cutesy mother,
who is very dear to me.
Soafer pretty.
Mother, strike a pose there,
Mother.
There you go!
And...
Go ahead, Mother.
And for sure, you know why we
are here today.
Of course,
it's the Pillar of Progress
Annual Awards Community Service.
And now, we will honor our
fellow citizen
who truly love and serve
our town, Bolagos.
And with us are our brave
police officers.
Hi!
Yes!
You know, I really admire them
because in events like this,
they protect us,
they take care of us.
And of course,
they always respond
when there are super dangerous
situations.
It's really dangerous!
Ka-Tirada guys...
In three months,
the crime rate in the country
has increased
by thirty-five percent.
Where will that lead us?
Robbery, holdup, abuse, rape,
and murder are rampant.
And according to the data,
addicts are often the culprits.
Oh my, it's driving me crazy!
When we watch the news,
all we see is bad news.
So it's good that there
are events like this
that can really restore our
faith in humanity.
Right or wrong?
As for me, I do believe that
they do deserve their awards,
that they should be truly
honored.
And of course, I know one
of the awardees today...
What, you want a clue?
Brave, efficient, kind,
hardworking,
and of course, handsome.
What? Are you excited, right?
May I request all the awardees
to proceed
to the backstage area.
This is it!
Miguel...
You're embarrassing.
The program is about to start.
There's just a sudden tip.
Everything is sudden
when it comes to you,
you're so hard to depend on.
You always have an excuse.
Just say that you have no
consideration for other people.
Mother, he's still not here?
Who's going to be happy?
The crime rate in the country
is getting worse and worse.
And do you know why?
Because there's something
even scarier
than criminals and syndicates.
The ones in uniform
and with badges.
They're the scariest.
They're the most dangerous.
The police,
who should be our protectors
but now the criminals and
syndicates are being protected.
This is okay.
Go ahead, Gonzalo,
let them pass.
But don't worry, Ka-Tiradas.
We won't stop fighting
for the truth.
Anyone,
anywhere.
What's inside?
We checked it, Sir.
The paper is clean. Good to go.
I want to see it.
Mother, just chill.
Maybe Father has an urgent
matter to attend to.
Urgent?
Isn't this urgent, too?
My child, do you know that some
of the awardees are here
two hours before their call
time?
They're here because this
is so important to them.
But your father?
Nothing. No word from him.
He doesn't even know
how to give updates.
Your Father, maybe he's busy
with something else.
That's why he's still not here.
Mother, let's just wait for him.
Father will still show up.
No need.
You know,
we're the only ones who are
being affected
because of his irresponsibility.
Let him explain to the organizer
when he gets here.
Mother, where are you going?
I'm going home.
What?
I have more important things
to do in my life than wait here.
Run, hurry!
Call for backup!
Aren't we starting yet?
We're going to cover something
in Amoroso.
They say they're still waiting
for someone.
Another awardee
who is a police officer.
Troublemaker.
Later, later.
Sir Andrew is busy.
Later, just go back.
You're getting in the way.
Hello, hello.
Boss, sorry. They're stubborn.
Okay, that's okay.
Okay, take a picture of us.
Okay. I'll just take a picture.
Just a group pic.
One...
One, two, three...
That's it!
Grandmother...
Are you okay?
Do you want to take a picture
with me?
Okay, I'll take a picture.
Okay.
Help me.
Smile.
- Thank you.
- Oh my god...
Andrew, Andrew, look.
That's Bolagos.
The chase is still ongoing.
Posted 1 minute ago.
It looks like it's still
ongoing.
Look for the upload.
Full footage if there is one.
Okay, Boss.
-Got it. We'll gather the intel.
-Put that video on the feed.
I'm going live.
Your number cannot be completed
as dialed.
Please check the number
and dial.
Where is the backup?
Ramon is still not answering,
Sir.
Who are the police chasing
and what's in the truck
they're carrying?
But the bigger question,
Ka-Tiradas,
is why did it come to this?
Did someone break protocol?
You can be rest assured
that if someone is involved,
we'll make sure someone is held
accountable.
Hey!
We can't go far!
The tire blew!
Try to stop,
I'll blow your skull off.
Make sure everyone involved
is caught on camera, okay?
Move!
Andrew, where are you going?
Someone's shooting!
Stupid!
Grandmother...
Grandmother, are you okay?
Let's get out of here,
Grandmother.
Hey guys, I'm still here
at Bolagos National High School,
where the awarding ceremony
was disrupted.
Because of this.
Here. That's it.
There's an armed man
in that truck.
Come on!
There are civilians. Be careful.
Sir, don't!
I'm not with them!
Cruz, cover me!
- Ouch.
- Andrew!
You take care of Grandmother.
Okay. Why? What are you going
to do?
I'll cover the shootout.
Andrew, it's dangerous!
Take care of Grandmother.
Let's finish that cop.
Let's go together.
Who are you?
Check it out.
You're so stupid.
Are you looking for me?
Go ahead and shoot.
This kid is dead.
Shoot!
What?
You can't do it.
If I were you,
drop what you're holding.
Drop it!
You're not allowed here!
Get out of here!
Let go of that kid.
I'll take care of you.
I'm not stupid!
I don't have a weapon anymore.
Let her go.
I don't care!
If I were you, let me go
so we can keep this kid alive.
What?
Don't be annoying!
Just give up! You can't escape!
What are you saying?
I'll kill you.
I'm not afraid of you.
My father said...
Never say die!
What?
Are you okay?
Of course, Father.
You're here.
Then, the caller,
I sent you the text.
Andrew, what happened to you?
Are you okay?
Update.
What's in the truck?
Congratulations, Major Delgado.
This looks like a solid hit.
Thank you, Chief.
Captain Olarve's team will
take custody from here.
Affirmative, Sir.
And we'll handle the inventory
and take it to the lab
for verifications.
Thank you, Captain.
How much is the street value
of that, Cap?
Based on intel,
800 million pesos,
rough estimate.
800 million?
Sir, you saved an entire city
of addicts.
This is a huge shipment.
But I'm sure there's someone
bigger behind this.
For sure.
The drug bust operation here
in the province of Bolagos
is now under control.
Job well done, Bolagos Police.
But the town's tirade is,
was it really just a simple
operation
or is it a drug deal gone wrong?
Cut.
Okay.
Let's go inside.
We'll just change the battery,
Sir.
Okay, thank you.
Grandmother...
Grandmother,
why are you still here?
I thought you had gone home
already.
I haven't said thank you yet.
Oh my, Ka-Saludos!
Too bad the ceremony
didn't push through today
because of what happened.
But I'm still really proud
of my father.
Later, we'll try to interview
him?
If he agrees.
Okay, Ka-Saludo guys!
Okay, okay, I'll get back
to you.
See you guys later!
But, Grandmother,
I hope you go home.
And, I promise,
I'll be good at my job,
especially since I know you're
watching.
Thank you very much.
We'll go ahead.
Okay.
Take care.
Wow...
That's great, he's kind.
You're so sweet, aren't you?
What chapter is that in your
Boss Budol Guide Book?
The good guy angle.
You look familiar.
You're so OA.
Well, that was just one
incident, right?
Okay, show me your data.
Right, right.
That's why.
My basher.
JoeyOnDuty?
Am I right?
That's me,
but I'm not a basher.
I'm a legit content creator
making legit content.
Wow!
You know, it's a good thing
I caught up with you
because I have a lot of
questions
about your anti-police tirades
and your budol tactics.
That's great.
You're really no different,
right, in person and on video?
Same confidence, same arrogance,
same no substance, right?
Wow...
It's just noise.
Wow, look who's talking, someone
who is trying to be deep.
But we're just the same.
We're both real talk.
You know the only difference
between us?
You just have more ring light.
You're funny.
Guys, let's go back to work.
The real journalism.
We don't have a name yet,
but it's not a small syndicate.
We have two in custody thanks
to the brave police officers,
Major Miguel Delgado
and Master Sergeant Steve Cruz.
Major,
how did you know about this kind
of drug transport?
I think this is your second time
intercepting
this kind of operation,
isn't it?
You're very lucky.
Or maybe you have inside
knowledge
about this kind of shipment.
What do you want to point out
with your question?
Get straight to the point.
It's not that hard to answer
my question
if you're not hiding anything.
I'm not hiding anything,
but with the tone of your voice,
it seems like you want to say
that I'm an accomplice in this.
Are you involved?
Let's save it for the press
conference.
Thank you. Let's go, Major.
You're really savage.
Let's go?
Yeah.
Why are you so brutal
to the police officers?
800 million pesos worth of shabu
was seized, right?
How many families could be
ruined because of that.
But you don't care, do you?
What? Because you're just
thinking,
you want to ruin people who are
already gambling their lives?
That's why you're just
a vlogger.
You're just being superficial.
News has layers.
You have to dig deeper.
But, word of advice.
What if you just do
beauty content or lifestyle?
Because you might be successful
with that.
Leave journalism
to real journalists.
Okay,
JoeyOnDuty?
Let's go?
Yeah, let's go.
Are you sure?
You're not in any pain?
You didn't break a bone
or hit your head?
Mother...
I should have brought you
with me earlier.
Mother, I'm fine.
Of course, Father is with me.
Of course, Father saved me!
It's a good thing he's
a sharpshooter, right,
Father?
So what if you get unlucky,
suddenly miss, and gets hit?
And you,
why did you gamble
with your daughter's life?
I wouldn't shoot
if I wasn't sure.
You don't know that.
A lot could happen, Miguel.
Maybe instead of being
praised for being alive.
They'll give you a standing
ovation
with your feet level
on the ground.
Maybe if they honor me
when I'm dead, you'd be there.
Are you blaming me for leaving?
-We've been waiting for a while!
-I'm following a lead!
Mother, Father, it's okay.
The important thing
is we're safe now,
and we're together, right?
Let's eat.
Let's eat, Love.
Go ahead and eat.
Mother.
What's this?
We're repacking shabu,
not pillows!
Repeat it!
That's a waste of space!
We're going to lose money!
- Yes, Boss. Sorry, Boss.
- Repeat it!
You guys!
Work properly!
- Yes, Boss.
- Yes.
Matias.
Almost one billion pesos
worth of drugs.
This is the second shipment
that went wrong.
I thought we already paid
the policeman at the checkpoint?
Ramon is on the payroll.
The one who's not is that pest
Delgado.
Why don't we just have him
killed?
Lisa,
I'll take care of Delgado.
I've already ordered Parak.
Your job is to find Ramon
because I heard he's gone into
hiding.
We should get ahead of him
before he confesses to his
fellow police officers.
I'm telling you, Andrew Dizon.
Everything you say,
you'll eat everything you say!
All your slander of the police!
Their heroism is so obvious,
and you're like that.
- You're insulting them!
- Hey Joey!
Who's your enemy?
Father.
I heard you downstairs.
I was wondering
who your enemy is.
Because I'm pissed
with that Boss Budol.
He disrespected you.
And he also picked on me.
Are you really serious
about your vlogging?
Of course!
Especially with people like him.
Do you know Father?
He has three million
subscribers.
That means that's how much
he fools with his fake news.
So, there should be someone who
shows the heroism of the police.
And that's me.
And...
Well, you see.
You and Mother are always
fighting
because you don't have time
for our family anymore
because of your work.
Sorry.
What's that for?
Sorry about what you said...
about my shortcomings to you
and your Mother.
Because I don't have time
for you anymore.
And you seldom visit here,
and that's what you see.
Father...
With Mother,
all you have to do is show
a little sweetness.
As for me, you don't need
to worry or do anything
because I understand
your job anyway.
Thank you.
But you know,
it's not important to me what
good I've done in this world.
What's more important to me
is you and your mother,
and your trust in me.
Of course, Father.
By the way,
I have a gift for you.
They say this is trendy now.
This is what is hung on
your bag.
- Ornaments.
- How cute!
I think I just saw
this version today.
Is this fake? Is this original?
This is the first time
I've seen something like this.
I don't know...
someone sold that at the
precinct.
I found it cute.
It's even wearing
a police uniform.
Cute, right?
You'll always keep this?
Hang it in your bag.
So even if I'm not by your side
and you have this with you,
it feels like we're still
together.
Yes, right?
Smile, please.
With teeth.
There.
- Right? Cute, right?
- Thank you, Father.
You'll always update me.
Don't be like your stubborn
father.
And by the way, go to bed early.
And always remember to eat
a lot for breakfast.
Because that's the most
important meal of the day.
Oh my Mother, why don't you just
record your instructions to me
so you don't get tired
of reminding me?
My child, I'll never get tired.
You know, Mother,
don't worry about me.
I sent you my location.
Also, don't worry about me here
in Manila
because Godfather Diego visits
me from time to time.
That's why I'm safe here.
Don't worry.
Mother, it looks like it's going
to rain again.
Okay, I'll hurry home.
Love you, Mother.
See you.
Okay. Bye. Love you.
This isn't a residential area
where Ramon's car is parked.
It's impossible for him
to leave it there.
His cellphone can't be reached,
Major.
His wife said his GPS
was last tracked in Sikatuna.
That's 25 kilometers away
from where his car was found.
It looks like he's hiding.
You're going to run away?
I won't run away!
And you're still planning
to hide from us.
No, Madam, no!
I really came here to see Parak.
Really?
Yes, Madam.
Believe me, Madam.
I won't run away.
Lloyd, check what that is.
Who's that?
Is there someone there?
You really have to do something
about that Miguel Delgado.
We've already lost twice
because of that cop.
What do you want to happen,
Boss?
In chess,
what do you do with a piece that
is an obstacle to your plan?
You knock it down.
Miguel is a problem.
He's a block in our system.
Andrew, what are you
investigating again?
If you're not up against
high government officials,
it's the police.
Every corner can be caught on
camera,
and they can use that
to identify you, Joey.